Marlborough, Mass. First Church records, 1704-2002.
Congregational Library & Archives
- Ministerial records, 1778 2002; 1778-2002; 18 Files; (12 folders, 6 volume)
  - Sylvester F. Bucklin Ordination Sermon, 1809 (Box 1, Volume 5)
    This is a softbound print volume of a sermon delivered by Pitt Clark for the ordination of Rev. Sylvester Bucklin.
    The full title reads: "A Sermon Delivered in Marlborough at the Ordination of the Rev. Sylvester F. Bucklin November 2, 1808."
  - Bucklin's Fiftieth Anniversary Sermon, 1859 (Box 1, Volume 6)
    This is a softbound print volume of a Sermon preached by Rev. Sylvester F. Bucklin on the fiftieth anniversary of his ordination.
    The full title reads: "A Sermon Preached in Marlborough, Mass., Nov. 3, 1858, by Rev. Sylvester F. Bucklin, on the Fiftieth Anniversary of his Ordination as Pastor of the East Church in that Town."
  - Reverend Charles Forbush records, 1832 1834; 1832-1834 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    This folder contains personal and church correspondence of Rev. Charles Forbush. Included in the records are the records of an Ecclesiastical Council meeting held at Forbush's house, and his acceptance of calls to settle in the Evangelical Church in Marlborough and the Congregational Church Society in Northbridge.
  - Reverend John N. Goodhue records, 1836 1839; 1836-1839 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Reverend George E. Day records, 1840 1846; 1840-1846 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Reverend Kent newspaper clipping, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Reverend William Brinsmead records, 1842 1889; 1842-1889 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Reverend David L. Ogden records, 1848 1850; 1848-1850 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Reverend Levi A. Field records, 1853 1880; 1853-1880 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Levi A. Field's Sermons, 1960; 3 Volumes (Box 1, Volume 7)
    Three copies of a printed volume of select sermons preached by Rev. Levi A. Field while a minister in Marlborough.
    The full title reads: "Sermons Preached by Rev. Levi A. Field Late Pastor of the Union Church and Society Marlboro, Mass. with the Funeral Sermon and Obituary by Rev. Edmund Powse, Sherborn, Mass."
  - Levi A. Field's "History of the Church" and Sylvester Bucklin's 50th Anniversary Sermon, 1858 1859; 1858-1859 (Box 3, Volume 1)
    This volume includes a history of the church written by Levi A. Field and the exercises from the celebration of the fiftieth anniversary of Reverend Sylvester Bucklin's ordination.
  - An Historical Sketch of the First Congregational Church, 1859 (Box 1, Volume 4)
  - Reverend Robert Breck records, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Reverend George Anthony records, 1860 1868; 1860-1868 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Architectural and Property drawings, 1866 1963; 1866-1963; 10 Items
  This series contains architectural drawings and property plans for the Union Society and First Church in Marlborough.
  - Plan of the Commons owned by the Union Society in Marlborough, surveyed by George Ellis, 1866 (Folder 1, Item 1)
  - Lands of Union Society of Marlborough, surveyed by George Ellis, 1866 (Folder 1, Item 2)
  - Plan of Land in Marlborough, 1866 (Folder 1, Item 3)
  - Plan of Land in Marlborough, surveyed by George Ellis & Son, copied by M.P. Rogers, 1866 (Folder 1, Item 4)
  - Photocopy of Sanborn Map of Marlborough, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Land Plan of Marlborough, surveyed by M. P. Rogers, 1887 (Folder 1, Item 5)
  - Plan of Land owned by the Union Church in Marlborough, 1902 (Folder 1, Item 6)
  - Plan of Union Society Parsonage Land, undated (Folder 1, Item 7)
  - Alterations to the existing Sunday School Assembly Room for the First Church, architect Earl V. Aldrich, 1963; 2 Items (Folder 1, Item 8-9)
- Microfilm, 1982; 1 Reels
  This series contains a single microfilm reel of early church records from the First Church in Marlborough.
  - Marlborough Church records, 1982; Contents were microfilmed by the Harvard University Reprographic Services. (Reel 1)
    This reel contains three volumes of early church records from the First Church and First Parish.
    Church Records Vol. 1
    Church Records Vol. 2
    Parish Records